hello and welcome to another bug Bounty
case study this time I extracted all the
cross-site scripting reports from recent
years to learn how people actually
making money with exercises because we
all associate them with alerts popping
up everywhere but there were many
questions bothering me for example how
are people actually showing impacts do
they just show the alert or do they
actually escalate do they bypass CSP or
do they just report an exercise without
the bypass or what payloads are people
using and payloads from all those
reports is exactly what I will show you
in this video enjoy
this time the scope of the study was 174
reports which is more than in case of
the ssrf case study but there was many
more reports but I restricted myself to
only the ones from the last three years
to avoid having to deal with older
Technologies older exercise or things
like flash or browser xss auditors
so here we have reports from 2020 up to
2022 or there is an exception for
reports with 5 000 Bounty or more in
this case I included uh even older
reports and out of those the most common
payload was EMG on our combination which
occurred 40 times
I actually didn't expect it I thought
that the script payload the script tag
will be the most common but I'm really
happy to see the the owner error
attribute being more popular but I would
like this this ratio to be even more in
favor of the EMG tag why is that because
when we have the
script tag
it doesn't give us any advantages over
the the image tag yet
it gives us some disadvantages there are
some things that um that the image tag
does better for example when we have an
A Dom exercise using inner HTML
attribute inner HTML assignment
it will not work with the script tag if
we use the the most typical payload here
this will not work because the script
tag cannot be used like this directly
using the inner HTML assignment which
may cause us to miss an exercise in
which we could otherwise find if we
would use the the image payload the
image pilot looks like this
in the most common form of course it
wasn't always exactly the same in all
the reports but but in most of them it
looked like this
and we can see that exactly the same
assignment results in alert popping up
this payload simply means that we have
EMG tag which is an image as you
probably could guess then we have source
of the image which should be something
that doesn't return an image in this
case we can see the the 404
here and then there is event handler
which fires on the on error attribute
and here the value of this attribute is
the JavaScript code that gets executed
after this event there are also a few
tricks that you can use here for example
if you have to bypass some filters you
can
instead of using the space between the
tag and the attribute name you can also
use the forward slash it also works
you can also use the slash between
attributes but not in this form if I run
this it does not work the image did
refresh the the image is rendered but
for us to be able to use the forward
slash between different attributes of
the tax between the SRC and on error
attribute we would have to use the
quotes around the source the value of
the source attribute we can see it works
again but if we are all already using
the the quotes here we do not even need
this this character we can simply use it
like this this may be very handy for for
some bypasses
and in case of of this the first one the
first attribute we cannot use nothing we
cannot use quotes it won't work it's
like an attack where
I think this whole part is treated as
the the tag name so it will not work
so it has to either be a forward slash
or a white space I believe things like
new line work as well
yes yes they do but but nothing
nothing else
so in my opinion we should be using the
image tag to
to detect access we should use it over
the script tag in the beginning because
it gives us more advantages and the
other advantages is that
even if my target has some sanitization
and my payload
from the honor attribute will be thrown
out
I will still see the image being
rendered on the page I will still see
this this little icon right here
which will show me that I can inject
HTML into the website
I just can't execute JavaScript code and
then I would start to
to work to bypass the sanitizer if I
would use the script tag and it would be
removed completely
I would not see it on the page I would
have to take a look at the source of the
page find the place where it should be
but it's not there so this is this is
harder
however there are situations when we
need the script tag because
if we have a website with content
security policy enabled then in this
case that the content security policy is
very very restrictive
then we will not be able to use the the
image tag the the image obviously we can
use the image stack but we cannot use it
for an xss because it requires the
unsafe inline directive in content
security policy which in proper content
security policies there is no unsafe
inline attribute and the thing is that
we have many ways of bypassing content
security policy
but for most of them we do need the
script tag because for example
if we even if we find a script that's on
whitelisted domain and we can use
something like script
SRC and here we have the white listed
domain
we have to use the script tag for that
with the event handlers there is pretty
much nothing we can try
so what to do if we have the injection
point in the inner HTML assignment as
I've shown you earlier and we want to
use the script tag
but
in this case
it will not if it will not work because
because of the inner HTML assignment we
can use
something like iframe SRC dock which is
which looks like this
and
so we have an iframe here which actually
has an SRC dock attribute which is like
the source of the iframe
and even though we are still inside the
inner HTML assignment
we can use the script tag inside the
iframe so we cannot use the script deck
directly
but we can use the iframe with the SRC
dock attribute and the script tag inside
when I run this we can see that even
though I was using the inner HTML
assignment
I could exploit an exercise
with this way with the script tag and we
can see that also the origin of this the
domain of this of this iframe is
remained the same it is not null
original or something that would make
the access invalid or hard to exploit it
is still the same domain so if you have
an inner HTML based xss and you have
content security policy
then you have to use the the script tag
to bypass it so so in the real life
obviously
the the way I I showed you here requires
the same unsafe inline directive in
content security policy but in the real
life you would have to use script SRC
and here you need to find
a white listed domain a whitelist that a
white listed script or some jsonp
endpoint or whatever
bypassing CSP could be a subject on its
own
next we'll step into the JavaScript
protocol which is
divided into two categories I would say
the JavaScript protocol is
looks like this so for example when we
have a link a normal link would have
HTTP or https protocol
but we can also use the JavaScript
protocol which
is very rarely used in in actual
websites but it is a perfect Vector for
exercises we can see that this this big
element is a element which is a link uh
graph is the target of the link and it
has the JavaScript protocol when I click
this the alert pops up so this is the
xss
and there are like two categories
um I divided it and one outlier one
category is something like this where
the attacker or the hunter I should say
was only able to use this as the link
Target so so basically as h a href and
the victim had to click this this link
to be attacked
and the other category was JavaScript in
one way or another opening this URL
directly so I don't know using window
open function location however or
something like this and the victim
didn't have to click on the link to
to execute the xss we can still see that
most of them anyway require some kind of
user interaction because many of them
are just reflected exercises
but
if we get into more details many of
these interactions was
a victim opening a URL so a normal
reflected exercise
but in these ones that were href or that
was also one report with with form
action
the victim would have to click the link
or click a button so that's like also a
user interaction but in practice it's
more interaction because it might be two
clicks or or one click plus one stored
xss
so that's that's more interaction
and we can see a big names being
mentioned here because
there are not that many of these
exercises only 23 but take a look the
average Bounty is six and a half
thousand dollars wide while the average
for all the reports was only four and a
half thousand dollars so very
significant difference and I think the
reason for it is that we have five times
Facebook here and five times Google in
the top which which obviously pay a lot
and we also have here some smaller
programs uh Shopify three times some
undisclosed ones but we can see that
people have problems with with this
pseudo protocol with this JavaScript
protocol probably many developers don't
even know about it because as I've said
I think I've seen it once being used on
a real website
and all the other usages are just
accesses personally I've also found
found a few exercises with this so
so definitely
definitely worth knowing about it and
what I'd like to mention is that there
were two bypasses where Hunters
were able to inject
white space characters so a space or I
believe a horizontal tab
inside the
the protocol and it still works
there we go
this should also execute in the browser
I think it can be percent zero nine per
or percent 20 or a new line
and the browser still treats it as a
valid JavaScript protocol otherwise
it is quite hard to to mess up with with
this inside the browser the browser is
quite strict when it comes to protocols
so so not much you can do than that we
also had some like custom filters where
you would inject one tag inside another
or things like that and also two cases
with with encoding bypasses some kind of
encodic viruses
and the next group of Pilots that I've
separated are other event handlers of
course
categorizing these Pilots is very
difficult because on one hand I want to
save all the details about the reports
but not on the other hand
I have to somehow merge similar ones so
so statistically it makes sense to look
at them as a whole and other event
handlers were payloads that also used
exercises in like image on error it's an
even Handler but it wasn't an image
stack or it wasn't an another attack
sometimes it was just the preference
because there is actually nothing
magical about the image tag it works on
these even handlers Works work on all
the HTML elements
so sometimes it was just the preference
of the hunter to use zombie girls
sometimes it was motivated by by the
vafs or by filters
any in other cases
um there were there were there were
other motivations for example we have
here some bypass where the Hunter
had some some filter
bypassed it using the nested tag inside
and what I'd like to highlight here is
he was using the mouse over attribute
which is which fires when you hover a
mouse over the element so it requires
user interaction
but the hunter was able to bypass the
filter with this and then before
submitting the payload he or she I don't
know
changed the attribute from on Mouse over
to unfocus with the autofocus attribute
so it does not require user interaction
it does not the final payload does not
require the victim to hover a mouse over
this element but it will fire
immediately which reduces the user
interaction
which likely can get you more bounties
on the other hand here we have a report
where I felt that the hunter could also
get more from the report
by creating another payload by using
another payload
this is in Alibaba
and there is some thought process about
bypassing a filter it's all good but on
in the end the hunter used the image
stack with the on click attribute there
was like a nested JavaScript inside
which was removed by the filter really
really fun fun
the report
but in the end he left it with the
on-click attribute which means the
victim has to click on the image to get
attacked which is a user interaction
which is I think unnecessary of course I
don't know all the details but there are
dozens of payloads that that do not
require the user interaction in this way
do not require the victim to cover a
mouse over something
for example you you can go to Ports
figure cheat sheet
and here you can input what tag you can
use what event handlers you can use
there are I think
250 event handlers or something like
this
and I am pretty sure that this Hunter
could achieve this exercise without the
user interaction and maybe a bigger
payout maybe guys from Alibaba thought
that they can escalate it by themselves
but there is a chance that that the
hunter here left some money on the table
so remember about trying to prepare your
payloads so they require as little user
interaction as possible
then next group of payloads are payloads
from xss Hunter it's a tool for blind
exercise which
of course in in most of cases here led
to a blind exercise and
often Hunters didn't even know where the
the payload fired some of these reports
are just hello I get a pink from
exercise Hunter and I do not know much
about where did this fire or why did
this fire
I think this is one of the shortest
reports that I've seen especially that
it is a valid one and rewarded three
thousand dollars
in the initial message the hunter only
said that he doesn't know where his
access Hunter script is
but then he realized that he can extract
it from the referral header so he gave
more details but Shopify team knew what
to do so so he was rewarded for it and
in many cases this accesses Hunter
payloads where reports were looking like
this just an access Hunter fire not much
more information that the hunters know
sometimes a screenshot
but but usually nothing also no filter
by pieces because it's really hard to
buy as a filter when you don't know
where your payload is
is being rendered so I'm pretty sure
that there are many blind exercises out
there but in spots where we can't see
the the payloads after filtering or
after sanitization and we just cannot
find them easily
so yeah not not much information
extracted from these reports
also xss Hunter will be deprecated in
March 2023 so we have to find an
alternative I don't know yet what tool
will I be using but but we have to to
think about it we have to find something
else
here I'd like to take a while to thank
all the bibiary premium members for
making the case study possible it's
actually a deal on which everyone
benefits because you get access to the
case study the full case study is on the
member platform I get to dedicate time
to do these case studies which I really
like and otherwise I probably couldn't
dedicate as much time to to do it
regularly and actually everyone else
non-members also benefit because
as this video shows I'm always
disclosing about one third of the case
study probability so that everyone
benefits and everyone everyone can can
learn something so thank you for this
next we step onto the category SVG which
was which were SVG files
in most cases these were file uploads
image uploads SVG files are images that
can also be valid
HTML and they can contain script tags
they can contain JavaScript code inside
so very very useful for this
we can see that the average Bounty for
for them is quite low I don't think this
is much of a trend I think it is a bit
unlucky I don't see any any reason why
these these exercises would be rewarded
lower we can see that all of them were
stored because these were file uploads
but in some of them the victim would
have to open a URL with the file so it
is pretty much a random URL which makes
the impact a little bit lower than a
stored exercise which Fires for example
on the main page or on the page that the
victim would visit
otherwise here the the attacker would
have to trick the victim into visiting a
URL which
makes the impact similar to a reflected
xss and probably a bit higher but but
similar so uh so that's about svgs
remember to to always test for them when
you can upload an avatar upload an image
or pretty much any file
we also have hero one of the very few
reports that used more advanced HTML
features in this case it was SVG with
foreign object tag
so we are talking about HTML namespace
is something I did learn a bit about
this year and I have some reports that
that I will hopefully disclose in some
time
but I was hoping to find more reports
like this during this case study
unfortunately not and I think this is
like the only one that that relies on
this more advanced mechanisms it was in
gitlab and it was only rewarded one and
a half thousand dollars
foreign
payloads which I will not dedicate the
whole category for for each of them
because it's rather boring we have a lot
of occurrences of the SVG onload
combination so the SVG tag with the
onload attribute
to be honest
I do not know
if this is this has any advantages over
the image on error or the script tag I
would I would not use this pilot at all
I fully understand using SVG tag with
the combination with the script tag
but but SVG we've unload
um I I don't get what what the advantage
of this we also had one blind exercise
that didn't use the access Hunter but
did use blindf tool or something like
this
uh I didn't hear about it before but now
since the accesses Hunter is getting
deprecated I should probably probably
learn about it we also had
um one or two bypasses one one payload
with angularjs this was Prototype
pollution so also a very specific report
I also thought that it would be more
prototype polishing bugs but but there
weren't that many we had one cool Report
with uh without the CSP bypass
on gitlab
where the hunter could use the base
stack to
actually attack the victim without
bypassing the CSP because the base stack
tells the the website that all the
relative URLs so so if you have any URL
for example just a slash
then if you have the base stack then it
would take your domain from the base
stack and then append the slash as the
path
so
it is hard to exploit it is difficult to
exploit and it is one of the ways to
have any impact if you can't bypass
content security policy because the base
base stack is another CSP directive
which is probably not as common as the
script SRC
and in this case the attacker was able
to turn this into an account account
takeover and he was rewarded fourteen
thousand dollars so
very very nice Bounty I think it was one
of the only report that that used this
we see that two times the combination of
iframe SRC the plus the script tag so
these are exercises that
were present in the inner HTML
assignment but Hunters used the script
tag either because they had to or
because they wanted to I didn't know
we also had two occurrences of the open
graph I think there was one open graph
protocol and one om bed which I think I
will cover in the next issue of vbr
premium because I think there are many
bugs to be found there
and we also had like one embed SRC tag
which I don't even know what it does
I think it was uh how we use the Airbnb
report from a few years ago
where I even have a video about it it
was like six different bypasses a CSP
bypass with swf file because this is the
older report so we're really really nice
one
and the other ones quite hard to to
classify but if you want if you have
access to the database if you remember
you can open the database see them one
by one and see if there's anything
interesting for you or not
so here you have totals for the amount
of reports and the average Bounty per
payload
if you want to get access to the full
case study which is on bbr premium
platform it's about two-thirds of the
study there and this video uploads plus
what was in the last issue of bbre
newsletter is about one-third if you
want to get access to the full one join
bbr premium you will also get access to
the database with all these reports so
you can even extend this case study but
what you want to know if you want to
join go to bbrew.dev premium for now
thank you for watching and goodbye